<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Exeter Observer - Independent public interest community journalism</title>

        <description>Editorially and financially independent, Exeter Observer delivers in-depth articles and investigative journalism that help people participate more effectively in local democracy</description>

        <link>http://localhost:3000</link>

        <generator>Jekyll v4.0.0</generator>

        <atom:link href="http://localhost:3000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>

        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 10:14:16 +0100</pubDate>

        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 10:14:16 +0100</lastBuildDate>

        

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Council abandons temporary COVID-19 cycling and walking safety plans in Exeter city centre</title>

                    
                        <description>Devon County Council cites &amp;quot;pushback&amp;quot; from traders as schemes on North Street, South Street, Fore Street and Cowick Street are scrapped. Meanwhile temporary changes in Topsham are dropped after &amp;quot;snap poll&amp;quot;.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>Devon County Council has abandoned its plans for temporary COVID-19 cycling and walking safety measures in Exeter city centre despite widespread support for the changes from survey respondents and consultees.

The proposed changes were to be funded under the first phase of a £250 million coronavirus emergency active travel fund announced by the Secretary of State for Transport on 9 May.

The county council has repeatedly said it would provide “improved foot and cycle access to the city centre via South S...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2020/08/04/devon-county-council-covid-19-temporary-cycling-and-walking-infrastructure-safety-plans-exeter-city-centre/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Transport &amp; mobility</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Devon county council</category>
                        
                            <category>Coronavirus</category>
                        
                            <category>Cycling &amp; walking</category>
                        
                            <category>Exeter city centre</category>
                        
                            <category>Topsham</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2020/08/04/devon-county-council-covid-19-temporary-cycling-and-walking-infrastructure-safety-plans-exeter-city-centre/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Is the &amp;quot;Net Zero&amp;quot; Exeter plan fit for purpose? Part I&amp;colon; Exeter&amp;apos;s carbon footprint</title>

                    
                        <description>Exeter City Futures&amp;apos; carbon reduction plan ignores over a million tonnes of carbon emissions and massively underestimates the challenges facing the city. First in a series examining its flaws by Fridays For Future youth climate activists.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>The Committee on Climate Change published its annual report on 25 June, two days before the anniversary of the UK’s carbon reduction pledge being signed into law. The report rebuked the government’s slow progress, urging much more dramatic action to avoid a post-pandemic emissions rebound.

The government nevertheless announced spending plans a few days later that dismayed environmental experts after spending billions of pounds during lockdown bailing out airlines, carmakers and oil companies without att...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2020/07/21/net-zero-exeter-2030-plan-part-one-exeters-carbon-footprint-exeter-city-futures-exeter-city-council-fridays-for-future-climate-activists/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Climate &amp; environment</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Net zero exeter</category>
                        
                            <category>Exeter city futures</category>
                        
                            <category>Exeter city council</category>
                        
                            <category>Climate crisis</category>
                        
                            <category>Fridays for future</category>
                        
                            <category>Carbon footprint</category>
                        
                            <category>Exeter airport</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2020/07/21/net-zero-exeter-2030-plan-part-one-exeters-carbon-footprint-exeter-city-futures-exeter-city-council-fridays-for-future-climate-activists/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Unelected Liveable Exeter Place Board created to oversee city from the shadows</title>

                    
                        <description>Exeter City Council has convened an unelected board that meets in private, does not publish its discussions or decisions and is taking responsibility for major policies which will determine Exeter's future.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>An assembly of the great and the good described by Exeter City Council’s chief executive, Karime Hassan, as “conscientious, talented people from all backgrounds who want to work in the best interests of the city” has been meeting in private in recent months.

Its membership is unelected, it does not publish its discussions or decisions and it is taking responsibility for major policies which will determine Exeter’s future.

The city council has had a predilection for such bodies for some time: recent arr...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2020/07/14/unelected-liveable-exeter-place-board-created-by-city-council-to-take-responsibility-for-major-policies-determining-Exeter-future-development/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Democracy &amp; governance</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Liveable exeter place board</category>
                        
                            <category>Exeter city council</category>
                        
                            <category>Property development</category>
                        
                            <category>Spatial development</category>
                        
                            <category>Accountability</category>
                        
                            <category>Transparency</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2020/07/14/unelected-liveable-exeter-place-board-created-by-city-council-to-take-responsibility-for-major-policies-determining-Exeter-future-development/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Exeter rough sleepers in COVID-19 emergency accommodation face uncertain future</title>

                    
                        <description>Exeter City Council has yet to confirm whether it will use any of the £2.15m Rough Sleeping Initiative funding it has received since 2018 to keep housing rough sleepers when government emergency accommodation funding runs out.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>When the coronavirus pandemic broke out, the government announced £3.2 million in emergency funding for local authorities to move all rough sleepers and other vulnerable homeless people into temporary accommodation. Each local authority allocation was based on the number of rough sleepers it reported in the autumn 2019 snapshot count.

Exeter’s performance in the count was poor: it reported the 25th highest number of rough sleepers among 316 local authorities in England, with a higher rate of rough sleep...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2020/06/10/exeter-rough-sleepers-covid19-emergency-accommodation-rough-sleeping-initiative-homelessness/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Community &amp; society</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Exeter city council</category>
                        
                            <category>Rough sleeping initiative</category>
                        
                            <category>Coronavirus</category>
                        
                            <category>Covid-19 emergency accommodation</category>
                        
                            <category>Night shelter</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2020/06/10/exeter-rough-sleepers-covid19-emergency-accommodation-rough-sleeping-initiative-homelessness/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Exeter City Council accepts climate emergency plan to make city carbon neutral by 2030</title>

                    
                        <description>Chief Executive warns that resourcing the plan is &amp;quot;problematic&amp;quot; given COVID-19 financial challenges and that lack of resources limits the council's capacity for immediate practical action.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>Exeter City Council has accepted a plan intended to make the city carbon neutral by 2030. At a meeting on Tuesday its Executive agreed to recommend that the Net Zero Exeter plan published by Exeter City Futures in April should be adopted by the council as a policy “to inform all policy documents, plans and corporate decision making in response to the climate emergency”.

The plan sets out a range of actions that Exeter City Futures believes can deliver the city council’s target of a carbon neutral Exeter...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2020/06/05/exeter-city-futures-net-zero-exeter-2030-plan-exeter-city-council-executive-decision/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Climate &amp; environment</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Exeter city council</category>
                        
                            <category>Climate crisis</category>
                        
                            <category>Net zero exeter</category>
                        
                            <category>Coronavirus</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2020/06/05/exeter-city-futures-net-zero-exeter-2030-plan-exeter-city-council-executive-decision/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Devon County Council fails to deliver promised COVID-19 cycling and walking infrastructure</title>

                    
                        <description>Deadline for action on social distancing for safe travel set by county cabinet member passes despite Devon receiving £1.7 million share of government emergency fund.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>Devon County Council has delivered none of the pop-up infrastructure it proposed to enable safe cycling and walking in Exeter during the coronavirus pandemic.

Andrew Leadbetter, county councillor for Wearside &amp; Topsham and Exeter’s only county cabinet member, confirmed that proposals outlined by the county nearly three weeks ago would be delivered by today.

However no changes have been made to the road layout on Fore Street, South Street, North Street, Cowick Street or Magdalen Road.

Andrew Leadbe...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2020/06/01/devon-county-council-cycling-walking-infrastructure-delivery-failure-department-for-transport-new-road-layouts-funding/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Transport &amp; mobility</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Devon county council</category>
                        
                            <category>Coronavirus</category>
                        
                            <category>Cycling &amp; walking</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2020/06/01/devon-county-council-cycling-walking-infrastructure-delivery-failure-department-for-transport-new-road-layouts-funding/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Coronavirus exposes council failure to deliver Exeter transport plans</title>

                    
                        <description>Devon County Council's failure to deliver overdue Exeter transport strategy and cycling and walking plan has led to an inadequate response to government demands for emergency coronavirus road layout changes.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>

Two weeks have passed since the government announced a £250 million emergency active travel fund in response to dramatic increases in walking and cycling during coronavirus lockdown.

The fund is intended to relieve pressure on public transport as lockdown eases by enabling local authorities to create pop-up bike lanes with protected space for cycling, wider pavements for pedestrians and car-free corridors to ensure higher levels of active travel can continue.

Public transport will only be able to car...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2020/05/22/devon-county-council-local-cycling-walking-infrastructure-plans-exeter-transport-strategy-department-for-transport-new-road-layout-for-coronavirus-social-distancing/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Transport &amp; mobility</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Devon county council</category>
                        
                            <category>Exeter transport strategy</category>
                        
                            <category>Local cycling &amp; walking infrastructure plan</category>
                        
                            <category>Covid-19</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2020/05/22/devon-county-council-local-cycling-walking-infrastructure-plans-exeter-transport-strategy-department-for-transport-new-road-layout-for-coronavirus-social-distancing/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Coronavirus halts decision to spend £3.9 million on car park repairs and upgrade</title>

                    
                        <description>Exeter City Council spending plans will be revisited in June at same time as Net Zero Exeter carbon reduction plan is discussed by Executive.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>A decision to spend at least £3.9 million on Exeter’s Cathedral and Quay multi-storey car park was deferred by Exeter City Council’s Executive in April, but will be revisited at its June meeting.

The city centre car park has been at risk of collapse since water leaked into the structure last winter. The four upper decks of the 355-space council-owned car park have been closed since January.


Exeter Cathedral and Quay car park top deck

A council report proposed spending £2.4 million to refurbish its lo...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2020/05/14/exeter-cathedral-and-quay-car-park-3.9m-refurbishment-capital-spending-decision/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Transport &amp; mobility</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Exeter city council</category>
                        
                            <category>Car parking</category>
                        
                            <category>Exeter net zero</category>
                        
                            <category>Climate crisis</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2020/05/14/exeter-cathedral-and-quay-car-park-3.9m-refurbishment-capital-spending-decision/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Exeter's first &amp;quot;zero carbon&amp;quot; housing development includes 96 car parking spaces for 40 homes</title>

                    
                        <description>Exeter City Council has approved plans to develop land at Pinhoe with a parking ratio of 2.4 cars per household as part of an &amp;quot;exemplar scheme for future residential development in the city&amp;quot; while accepting that zero carbon construction comes &amp;quot;at a cost to the provision of affordable housing&amp;quot;.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>In what may be an indication of development decisions to come, Exeter City Council planning committee approved plans for 40 new “zero carbon” homes on Monday night despite previously deferring the decision due to concerns about the development’s impact on congestion levels and the low proportion of affordable housing included in the scheme.

The proposal to develop the 3.9 acre greenfield site between Pulling Road and Church Hill in Pinhoe initially included 100 car parking spaces, but a council report r...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2020/05/08/pulling-road-pinhoe-exeter-net-zero-carbon-affordable-housing-car-parking-congestion/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Planning &amp; place</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Exeter city council</category>
                        
                            <category>Net zero exeter</category>
                        
                            <category>Affordable housing</category>
                        
                            <category>Devon county council</category>
                        
                            <category>Car parking</category>
                        
                            <category>Congestion</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2020/05/08/pulling-road-pinhoe-exeter-net-zero-carbon-affordable-housing-car-parking-congestion/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Exeter rough sleepers night shelter to open all year round</title>

                    
                        <description>Exeter City Council has approved plans to extend Magdalen Street night shelter opening from April to the end of September.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>A night shelter that provides overnight accommodation for rough sleepers and homeless people in Exeter will now open all year round, following a planning decision by Exeter City Council.

The shelter, which is located inside the Magdalen Street gyratory at the head of Western Way in a building that was previously a series of bars and restaurants, has been open during the winter months since November 2018.

It will now also open from April to the end of September, when it will accommodate fourteen rough s...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2020/05/07/night-shelter-homeless-rough-sleepers-magdalen-street-exeter-bcha/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Community &amp; society</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Exeter city council</category>
                        
                            <category>Rough sleeping</category>
                        
                            <category>Complex needs</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2020/05/07/night-shelter-homeless-rough-sleepers-magdalen-street-exeter-bcha/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Cranbrook town centre community building application submitted</title>

                    
                        <description>Devon County Council is to develop new town centre facilities including a children's centre with public health nursing provision, youth centre with indoor and outdoor recreational spaces and library with small café.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>Devon County Council has applied for outline planning permission for a new community building for Cranbrook town centre.

The proposed building, which would be located near the junction of Tillhouse Road and Cranford Lane, includes a children’s centre with public health nursing provision, a youth centre with indoor and outdoor recreational spaces and a library with a small café.

It will be designed flexibly to host a range of Devon County Council services and to adapt to future changes in service provis...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2020/05/07/cranbrook-community-building-plans/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Planning &amp; place</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Devon county council</category>
                        
                            <category>Cranbrook</category>
                        
                            <category>Greater exeter</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2020/05/07/cranbrook-community-building-plans/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Exeter City Council announces £1.584m April budget shortfall caused by COVID-19 restrictions</title>

                    
                        <description>Council revenues have fallen dramatically during the coronavirus pandemic, prompting a £6.357 million capital spending deferment. But financial support from government has so far been limited.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>Exeter City Council announced an anticipated £1.584m budget shortfall for April at Tuesday’s full council meeting.

The meeting, which was held online, heard that revenues from car parking had fallen precipitously, down from a budgeted £170,000 to £1,000 a week.

It was also told that council-owned visitor attractions and entertainment venues were closed and adverse effects on collection of council tax, business rates, commercial rates and other debts were expected.

Council leader Phil Bialyk said: “The...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2020/04/24/exeter-city-council-announces-1.584-million-april-budget-shortfall-caused-by-covid-19-restrictions/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Democracy &amp; governance</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Exeter city council</category>
                        
                            <category>Covid-19</category>
                        
                            <category>Coronavirus</category>
                        
                            <category>Budget shortfall</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2020/04/24/exeter-city-council-announces-1.584-million-april-budget-shortfall-caused-by-covid-19-restrictions/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Half of COVID-19 support grants unclaimed by Exeter businesses</title>

                    
                        <description>Exeter City Council in bottom third of local authorities as only 45% of eligible local businesses claim government coronavirus support money.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>Exeter City Council has distributed less than half of the government’s coronavirus pandemic business support grant funding to local businesses in the city.

Just over 2,000 Exeter businesses are eligible for either the Small Business Grants Fund or the Retail, Hospitality and Leisure Business Grants Fund which local authorities in England are administering on behalf of the government.

Many businesses with premises that qualify for Small Business Rate Relief can claim a grant payment of up to £10,000 whe...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2020/04/22/half-of-exeter-city-council-covid-19-coronavirus-pandemic-business-grant-payments-unclaimed/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Economy &amp; enterprise</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Exeter city council</category>
                        
                            <category>Covid-19</category>
                        
                            <category>Coronavirus</category>
                        
                            <category>Business support grants</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2020/04/22/half-of-exeter-city-council-covid-19-coronavirus-pandemic-business-grant-payments-unclaimed/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>University of Exeter strike ends third week with rally and concert at St David's Church</title>

                    
                        <description>The Exeter branch of the University &amp; College Union (UCU) is taking part in four weeks of national industrial action over pensions, equal pay for female and BAME staff, increasing workloads and the use of casual employment contracts.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>Staff at the University of Exeter yesterday reached the end of a third week of industrial action over employment conditions.

Strikers marched through the city centre before holding a rally at St David’s Church which included free teaching sessions and a performance by protest singer Billy Bragg.

This round of industrial action began on 20 February with a two day strike, which was followed last week by a three day strike. This week’s four strike days are to be followed by five strike days next week.

Ac...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2020/03/06/exeter-university-college-union-strike-third-week-rally-concert/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Education &amp; skills</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>University of exeter</category>
                        
                            <category>Exeter ucu</category>
                        
                            <category>Higher education</category>
                        
                            <category>Pensions</category>
                        
                            <category>Zero hours contracts</category>
                        
                            <category>Casualisation</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2020/03/06/exeter-university-college-union-strike-third-week-rally-concert/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Is Exeter finally responding to the climate emergency?</title>

                    
                        <description>A surge of activity about action to combat climate change is taking place in Exeter, including the publication of a carbon neutral blueprint pending a &amp;quot;mobilisation summit&amp;quot;, but detail and evidence is still missing and community engagement is falling short of debate.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>Exeter City Council declared a climate emergency on 23 July 2019, despite having rejected a proposal to do so just five months earlier.

Nowhere in council minutes is there an absolute commitment to a date by when the city would be carbon neutral, but 2030 is the working assumption held by Exeter City Futures, the council’s chosen vehicle for mobilising the necessary changes.

A 2030 target was also reinforced by the council leader, Phil Bialyk, during the 2020/21 budget debate on 25 February.

Although ...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2020/03/05/exeter-city-futures-blueprint-carbon-neutral-2030-net-zero-mobilisation-summit-green-new-deal-devon-climate-emergency/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Climate &amp; environment</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Climate crisis</category>
                        
                            <category>Blueprint</category>
                        
                            <category>Exeter city futures</category>
                        
                            <category>Exeter city council</category>
                        
                            <category>Exeter net zero</category>
                        
                            <category>Oxygen house</category>
                        
                            <category>Fridays for future exeter</category>
                        
                            <category>Green new deal</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2020/03/05/exeter-city-futures-blueprint-carbon-neutral-2030-net-zero-mobilisation-summit-green-new-deal-devon-climate-emergency/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Exeter climate strike anniversary march brings junction to standstill</title>

                    
                        <description>Protestors form human chain around County Hall to highlight Devon County Council's role as key regional climate policy decision-maker after Exeter City Council confiscates banners promoting carbon neutral blueprint policies.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>Around 200 people took part in Exeter’s Youth Strike 4 Climate on Friday 14 February, marking the first anniversary of regular protests against lack of action in the city to tackle the climate crisis.

Young people across the world have participated in regular strikes since Swedish teenager Greta Thunberg staged a protest outside the Swedish parliament in August 2018 holding a sign that read: “School strike for the climate”.

Students from local schools, colleges and the University of Exeter were joined ...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2020/02/28/exeter-climate-strike-anniversary-march-blocks-city-centre-road-junction/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Climate &amp; environment</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Climate crisis</category>
                        
                            <category>Youth strike 4 climate</category>
                        
                            <category>Fridays for future</category>
                        
                            <category>Exeter city council</category>
                        
                            <category>Exeter city futures</category>
                        
                            <category>Exeter net zero</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2020/02/28/exeter-climate-strike-anniversary-march-blocks-city-centre-road-junction/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>University of Exeter PRISM network champions queer STEMM pioneers</title>

                    
                        <description>Exeter students celebrated the lives of polar explorer and botanist Elke Mackenzie, inventor, engineer and futurist Nikola Tesla and astronaut and children's author Sally Ride in winning LGBT+ network competition entries.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>The University of Exeter PRISM network for LGBT+ and allies who study or work in Science, Technology, Engineering, Mathematics and Medicine (STEMM) held its first competition last month.

Local students suggested pioneering queer STEMM figures to champion, with the three winning entrants giving presentations on their chosen pioneers at the February PRISM network meeting.



Madi Pollard-Shore discussed the work of polar explorer and botanist Elke Mackenzie who discovered new lichens in Antarctica whilst ...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2020/02/27/university-of-exeter-prism-queer-stemm-champions-competition-winners/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Community &amp; society</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>University of exeter</category>
                        
                            <category>Prism</category>
                        
                            <category>Stemm</category>
                        
                            <category>Lgbtqia+</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2020/02/27/university-of-exeter-prism-queer-stemm-champions-competition-winners/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Echoes of Exeter's Roman past reveal risks to city's future vision</title>

                    
                        <description>The unexpected discovery of Roman remains on Exeter's bus station redevelopment site suggests significant risks may also exist for the adjacent Citypoint regeneration scheme.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>Modern Exeter is built on the important Roman military settlement of Isca, where the 5,000-strong Second Augustan Legion were garrisoned for over twenty years. The civilian city developed around the fortress.

Archaeological discoveries of Roman remains have formed a staple of Exeter’s recent history, including a major survey of Cathedral Close in the 1970s and the discovery of a Roman military supply base between Topsham and Exeter city centre in 2015.

So it was not a great surprise to find yet more Ro...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2020/02/20/exeter-roman-remains-discovery-bus-station-leisure-centre-redevelopment-site-risk/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Planning &amp; place</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Roman exeter</category>
                        
                            <category>St sidwell's point</category>
                        
                            <category>Citypoint</category>
                        
                            <category>Bus station redevelopment</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2020/02/20/exeter-roman-remains-discovery-bus-station-leisure-centre-redevelopment-site-risk/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Exeter library children's horse to keep on rocking!</title>

                    
                        <description>A crowdfunding appeal has successfully raised £1000 to repair Exeter Central library's popular rocking horse, Jubilee Beauty.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>Exeter Central library has successfully raised £1000 in a crowdfunding appeal to make repairs to a rocking horse that has been resident in the children’s library since 1977.

The horse, Jubilee Beauty, will now receive the restoration needed to get it back in service, thanks to public generosity.

57 people contributed to the GoFundMe appeal, including Luis Gonzalez, who donated £485 on behalf of their daughter, who loves to ride the horse and is eager for it to return.

Luis Gonzalez said: “My five year...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2020/02/06/exeter-central-library-childrens-rocking-horse-crowdfunding-appeal-jubilee-beauty/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Community &amp; society</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Exeter central library</category>
                        
                            <category>Crowdfunding</category>
                        
                            <category>Rocking horse restoration</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2020/02/06/exeter-central-library-childrens-rocking-horse-crowdfunding-appeal-jubilee-beauty/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Exeter net zero housing revolution takes root in Chestnut Avenue</title>

                    
                        <description>Exeter City Council is taking exploratory steps from talking about a zero carbon future to delivering one with a pilot housing project in Wonford.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>The green shoots of a net zero housing revolution are to be found on Chestnut Avenue, in Exeter’s Wonford housing estate, where six of the city’s 5000 council-owned homes have been chosen to pilot a new approach to transforming existing houses into energy efficient, low maintenance homes.

The pilot has been developed by the city council in partnership with others including a company called Energiesprong UK. “Energiesprong”, which translates literally as “energy jump”, is the trade name of a commercial p...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2020/01/22/exeter-net-zero-carbon-housing-pilot-project-wonford-chestnut-avenue/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Planning &amp; place</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Exeter city council</category>
                        
                            <category>Net zero exeter</category>
                        
                            <category>Climate change</category>
                        
                            <category>Housing</category>
                        
                            <category>Retrofit</category>
                        
                            <category>Energiesprong</category>
                        
                            <category>Wonford</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2020/01/22/exeter-net-zero-carbon-housing-pilot-project-wonford-chestnut-avenue/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Exeter &amp; East Devon council accounts delayed by Grant Thornton's &amp;quot;lack of staff resources&amp;quot;</title>

                    
                        <description>Annual accounts for local government, including Exeter City Council, have been delayed by private sector firms failing to complete their work on time after cost-cutting government auditing reforms.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>Exeter City Council’s chief financial officer, Dave Hodgson, told a meeting of the council’s audit and governance committee on 4 December 2019 that the external auditors, Grant Thornton, had not yet provided their opinion on the council’s 2018/19 accounts even though the deadline for doing so was 31 July 2019.

Without that opinion, the accounts could not be approved formally and then published, thus delaying public scrutiny of the council’s financial affairs.

The delay also prevents the government from...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2020/01/03/exeter-city-council-accounts-delayed-grant-thornton-auditors-local-government-finance-conservative-private-sector-outsourcing/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Democracy &amp; governance</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Exeter city council</category>
                        
                            <category>East devon district council</category>
                        
                            <category>Accounts</category>
                        
                            <category>Grant thornton</category>
                        
                            <category>Auditors</category>
                        
                            <category>Local government audit reforms</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2020/01/03/exeter-city-council-accounts-delayed-grant-thornton-auditors-local-government-finance-conservative-private-sector-outsourcing/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Conservative vote share varies across Devon but still blocks an Independent MP in East Devon</title>

                    
                        <description>Labour loses vote share in every constituency, but retains Exeter and Plymouth Sutton &amp; Devonport to leave the county position unchanged from 2017.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>Apart from Devon East, where independent candidate Claire Wright was well-positioned to challenge 150 years of Conservative representation at Westminster, few people expected any of Devon’s twelve parliamentary constituencies to change hands at this election.

As predicted, a sea of blue still surrounds Exeter and Plymouth Sutton &amp; Devonport, both of which Labour held with reduced majorities.

The only South West seat that changed hands was Stroud, which has been marginal since 1997. Labour lost 5% o...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2019/12/15/2019-parliamentary-elections-devon-results-analysis-varying-conservative-performance-labour-losses/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Democracy &amp; governance</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>General election</category>
                        
                            <category>Plymouth sutton &amp; devonport</category>
                        
                            <category>Tiverton &amp; honiton</category>
                        
                            <category>Totnes</category>
                        
                            <category>Newton abbot</category>
                        
                            <category>Devon central</category>
                        
                            <category>Exeter</category>
                        
                            <category>Devon east</category>
                        
                            <category>Torbay</category>
                        
                            <category>Devon south west</category>
                        
                            <category>Devon west &amp; torridge</category>
                        
                            <category>Plymouth moor view</category>
                        
                            <category>Devon north</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2019/12/15/2019-parliamentary-elections-devon-results-analysis-varying-conservative-performance-labour-losses/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Conservatives hold Topsham in Exeter city council by-election</title>

                    
                        <description>A by-election held on general election day produced an unusually high turnout but a lower Conservative vote share than at the May local elections.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>Conservative candidate Keith Sparkes was elected to represent Topsham on Exeter City Council on Thursday.

He secured 2,315 votes on a 42.5% share. The turnout was unusually high at 74% as the vote was held on the same day as the general election.

However the Conservative vote share was 4.5% down in the ward compared with the May local elections, when Rob Newby was elected with 47% of the votes cast.

Labour’s Ivan Jordan finished second on this occasion with 1713 votes on a 31% share, up a point and a ...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2019/12/14/conservative-wins-exeter-topsham-byelection-reduced-vote-share/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Democracy &amp; governance</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Exeter city council</category>
                        
                            <category>Local elections</category>
                        
                            <category>By-election</category>
                        
                            <category>Topsham</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2019/12/14/conservative-wins-exeter-topsham-byelection-reduced-vote-share/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>East Devon Independent Claire Wright set to unite Remain voters in close historic two-way contest</title>

                    
                        <description>Claire Wright is poised to make history by beating the Tories in East Devon next week. If she does it will be without thanks to the LibDems and Greens, who insisted on standing candidates against her despite the preferences of local party members and the Unite to Remain campaign.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>Political hacks have become more of a nuisance than ice cream-snaffling seagulls on Exmouth sea front in recent weeks as national media coverage of Claire Wright’s campaign to unseat the Tories in East Devon has increased by the day.



Reporters who hadn’t already realised East Devon would be a 2019 general election hotspot began to notice the game was afoot when incumbent Hugo Swire announced in September that he would not stand.

Then last week’s MRP YouGov poll found that Claire Wright was the most l...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2019/12/05/2019-east-devon-independent-claire-wright-unite-remain-voters-general-election-green-party-lib-dems/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Democracy &amp; governance</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>General election</category>
                        
                            <category>East devon</category>
                        
                            <category>St. loyes</category>
                        
                            <category>Topsham</category>
                        
                            <category>Unite to remain</category>
                        
                            <category>Green party</category>
                        
                            <category>Liberal democrats</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2019/12/05/2019-east-devon-independent-claire-wright-unite-remain-voters-general-election-green-party-lib-dems/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Exeter climate strikers create human chain around County Hall</title>

                    
                        <description>Fridays for Future Exeter led a march through the city to form a human chain around County Hall in protest at climate change inaction.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>
</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2019/11/30/exeter-climate-strikers-create-human-chain-around-county-hall/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Climate &amp; environment</category>
                    

                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2019/11/30/exeter-climate-strikers-create-human-chain-around-county-hall/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>University of Exeter staff strike over pay, pensions and working conditions</title>

                    
                        <description>The Exeter branch of the University &amp; College Union (UCU) is taking part in a national eight day strike for fair pay and pensions, including equal pay for female and BAME staff, and against casualisation and increasing workloads.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>Staff at the University of Exeter were among more than 40,000 lecturers and other academic and support staff who walked out on strike at 60 UK universities on Monday in protest over pay cuts, increased pension costs and deteriorating working conditions.

Members of the University and College Union (UCU) began eight days of strike action after agreement could not be reached with university representatives over ongoing disputes which caused significant disruption on campuses across the country during last ...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2019/11/27/exeter-university-college-union-strike/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Education &amp; skills</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>University of exeter</category>
                        
                            <category>Exeter ucu</category>
                        
                            <category>Higher education</category>
                        
                            <category>Pensions</category>
                        
                            <category>Zero hours contracts</category>
                        
                            <category>Casualisation</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2019/11/27/exeter-university-college-union-strike/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>An integrated public transport service for Devon remains a distant aspiration</title>

                    
                        <description>A change to Exeter's G bus service operator has revealed the limits of Devon County Council's approach to transport system integration.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>Exeter’s G bus service runs between Polsloe and the quay via the city centre. Passenger numbers are not high, the main users being residents of the Polsloe area and the Shillhay estate by the river. Operating the service is not a viable commercial proposition, so it is provided under a contract subsidised by Devon County Council.

In May 2019 Country Bus replaced Stagecoach as the G service operator following a competitive tendering exercise. Information from the county council shows that there were two ...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2019/11/25/integrated-public-transport-devon-county-council-country-bus-stagecoach-exeter-g-service/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Transport &amp; mobility</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Devon county council</category>
                        
                            <category>Stagecoach south west</category>
                        
                            <category>Country bus devon</category>
                        
                            <category>Bus passenger information</category>
                        
                            <category>Integrated passenger transport</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2019/11/25/integrated-public-transport-devon-county-council-country-bus-stagecoach-exeter-g-service/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Will a new South West industrial strategy deliver what it promises?</title>

                    
                        <description>Our business-led Local Enterprise Partnership appears committed to a new approach to driving growth which its CEO describes as &amp;quot;game-changing&amp;quot;.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>The Heart of the South West Local Enterprise Partnership’s (LEP) new local industry strategy featured prominently at its annual conference in Torquay on 4 November despite it not yet having been published.

It has been signed off by all the partners and seen by other stakeholders, but will remain otherwise unseen until it receives ministerial-level clearance in Whitehall.

What are Local Enterprise Partnerships?

In 2010 the Conservative/Liberal Democrat coalition government published its blueprint for m...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2019/11/12/heart-of-the-south-west-local-enterprise-partnership-local-industrial-strategy/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Economy &amp; enterprise</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Heart of the south west lep</category>
                        
                            <category>Centre for progressive policy</category>
                        
                            <category>Inclusive growth</category>
                        
                            <category>Local enterprise partnerships</category>
                        
                            <category>Regional funding</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2019/11/12/heart-of-the-south-west-local-enterprise-partnership-local-industrial-strategy/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Exeter Labour support collapses in Heavitree &amp; Whipton Barton county by-election</title>

                    
                        <description>Greg Sheldon wins Devon County Council division by just 40 votes after Labour loses nearly a fifth of its previous vote share.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>

Labour support collapsed in yesterday’s Devon County Council by-election in Heavitree and Whipton Barton, a former party stronghold, as voters went to the polls to elect a replacement for Emma Brennan, who resigned in September. A standards investigation concluded earlier this year that she had brought the council into disrepute with her conduct and she was ordered to undertake anger management training.

Labour secured a comfortable victory in the previous county council election in 2017, with a major...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2019/10/25/exeter-heavitree-whipton-barton-byelection-devon-county-council-labour-vote-share-collapse/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Democracy &amp; governance</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Devon county council</category>
                        
                            <category>Local elections</category>
                        
                            <category>Heavitree &amp; whipton barton</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2019/10/25/exeter-heavitree-whipton-barton-byelection-devon-county-council-labour-vote-share-collapse/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Exeter City Council cuts scrutiny of executive decision-making</title>

                    
                        <description>Constitutional changes proposed by Exeter City Council will make it more difficult to hold the ruling political group to account.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>Exeter City Council’s executive, the group of leading councillors who run the authority’s business, have agreed a package of changes to the current scrutiny arrangements set out in the council’s constitution.

Taken together the changes weaken everyone’s capacity for challenging the executive. They will go for approval to a meeting of the full council next Tuesday 15 October.

Scrutiny committees were introduced as part of legislative reforms to local government which allowed councils to replace the old ...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2019/10/09/exeter-city-council-reduces-scrutiny-decision-making/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Democracy &amp; governance</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Exeter city council</category>
                        
                            <category>Democratic deficit</category>
                        
                            <category>Trust &amp; transparency</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2019/10/09/exeter-city-council-reduces-scrutiny-decision-making/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Exeter global climate strike march</title>

                    
                        <description>Fridays for Future Exeter led 3500 people on a climate crisis demonstration through the city as millions mobilised in 185 countries worldwide.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>
</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2019/09/21/exeter-global-climate-strike-march-photo-gallery/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Climate &amp; environment</category>
                    

                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2019/09/21/exeter-global-climate-strike-march-photo-gallery/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Exeter youth climate strikers launch Green New Deal for Devon</title>

                    
                        <description>Fridays For Future Exeter have published a detailed vision of a more equitable future that calls on elected representatives across the county to recognise the climate crisis as a symptom of a dysfunctional political economy.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>

Fridays For Future Exeter, the youth climate strikers who led 3500 people on a march through the city as part of today’s global climate strike, have launched a detailed vision for a Green New Deal for Devon.

In the fourteen page document they call on elected representatives across the county to recognise the climate crisis as a symptom of a dysfunctional political economy and to place it at the centre of every policy, planning and spending decision they make.

It focusses on the interdependence of cli...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2019/09/20/exeter-youth-climate-strikers-launch-green-new-deal-devon/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Climate &amp; environment</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Fridays for future</category>
                        
                            <category>Climate crisis</category>
                        
                            <category>Green new deal</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 17:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2019/09/20/exeter-youth-climate-strikers-launch-green-new-deal-devon/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Thousands march in Exeter for global climate strike as millions mobilise worldwide</title>

                    
                        <description>Fridays for Future Exeter led 3500 people on a climate crisis demonstration through the city backed by dozens of organisations on the eve of the UN Climate Action Summit in New York.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>

An estimated 3500 people marched through Exeter today as part of a global climate strike that saw more than 200 similar events take place across the UK, with millions demonstrating in 185 countries worldwide.

The march, which was led by Fridays for Future Exeter, part of the UK Student Climate Network, gathered in Bedford Street before setting off to County Hall via the High Street. So many people took part that the head of the march reached Magdalen Street before its last members had set off.

A samb...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2019/09/20/exeter-global-climate-strike-climate-crisis-green-new-deal/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Climate &amp; environment</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Global climate strike</category>
                        
                            <category>Youth strike 4 climate</category>
                        
                            <category>Fridays for future</category>
                        
                            <category>Climate crisis</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2019/09/20/exeter-global-climate-strike-climate-crisis-green-new-deal/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Education union challenges university to address widespread casualisation of teaching staff</title>

                    
                        <description>Exeter University &amp; College Union (UCU) launched an anti-casualisation campaign on Friday as a prelude to negotiation with the University of Exeter over academic staff contracts.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>

Exeter University &amp; College Union (UCU) has launched a campaign to address widespread casualisation of academic staff at the University of Exeter.

The education union’s new general secretary, Jo Grady, introduced the initiative at a launch event on Friday.



She pointed at Higher Education Statistics Agency (HESA) figures for 2016-17 that show 64% of all academic staff at the University of Exeter are employed on insecure contracts.

The figures reveal that only 1275 of the university’s 3520 acade...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2019/09/17/exeter-university-college-union-launches-anti-casualisation-campaign/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Education &amp; skills</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>University of exeter</category>
                        
                            <category>Exeter ucu</category>
                        
                            <category>Higher education</category>
                        
                            <category>Zero hours contracts</category>
                        
                            <category>Casualisation</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2019/09/17/exeter-university-college-union-launches-anti-casualisation-campaign/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Exeter Extinction Rebellion Wave of Water march</title>

                    
                        <description>Extinction Rebellion campaigners marched through Exeter city centre led by a samba band and dressed in blue to represent a wave of water, highlighting rising sea levels and the coming global water crisis.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>
</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2019/09/14/exeter-extinction-rebellion-wave-of-water-fashion-industry-march-photo-gallery/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Climate &amp; environment</category>
                    

                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2019/09/14/exeter-extinction-rebellion-wave-of-water-fashion-industry-march-photo-gallery/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Exeter protest misses its mark by mixing its messages</title>

                    
                        <description>One of Exeter's biggest ever street demonstrations combined anti-Brexit and pro-democracy concerns to produce a confused protest against government policy.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>An estimated two thousand people packed Exeter’s Bedford Square on Saturday 31 August to protest against the government’s Brexit policies and its highly controversial decision to prorogue parliament for five weeks from 10 September.

Exeter MP Ben Bradshaw said it was one of the biggest gatherings he had seen in the 23 years he has represented the city, and paid tribute to Conservative MPs prepared to put national interest before party loyalty.

South West MEP Caroline Voaden argued that the European Par...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2019/09/03/exeter-anti-government-protest-prorogation-parliament-brexit-no-deal/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Democracy &amp; governance</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Brexit</category>
                        
                            <category>Democracy</category>
                        
                            <category>Prorogation</category>
                        
                            <category>Referendum</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2019/09/03/exeter-anti-government-protest-prorogation-parliament-brexit-no-deal/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Mock funeral march brings Exeter city centre to a sombre standstill</title>

                    
                        <description>Extinction Rebellion campaigners brought the gravity of the ecological emergency home to Exeter on Saturday in a funereal procession commemorating wildlife loss caused by climate change.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>As the summer’s second heatwave came to an end, around 150 people joined a funereal procession through Exeter city centre to highlight the destruction caused by climate change and to promote the urgent need for radical action if further devastation is to be avoided.

Pall bearers carrying a coffin representing the death of the natural world were led by a mute chief mourner, head shrouded, who slowly beat a drum to announce the cortège that followed. Dressed in black from head to toe with faces powdered w...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2019/07/30/exeter-extinction-rebellion-funeral-march-climate-crisis-wildlife-loss/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Climate &amp; environment</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Extinction rebellion</category>
                        
                            <category>Climate crisis</category>
                        
                            <category>Biodiversity</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2019/07/30/exeter-extinction-rebellion-funeral-march-climate-crisis-wildlife-loss/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Exeter Extinction Rebellion Funeral march</title>

                    
                        <description>Extinction Rebellion campaigners brought Exeter City Centre to a standstill with a funereal procession commemorating wildlife loss caused by climate change.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>
</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2019/07/27/exeter-extinction-rebellion-funeral-march-photo-gallery/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Climate &amp; environment</category>
                    

                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2019/07/27/exeter-extinction-rebellion-funeral-march-photo-gallery/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Exeter could do better - was there no alternative to closing so many public toilets?</title>

                    
                        <description>Exeter City Council did not need to close thirteen public toilets to balance the books. The money to keep them open was available in reserves, but no mention of this option was made during public decision-making by councillors or officers.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>Exeter City Council’s decision to close thirteen of the city’s public toilets was reported by Exeter Observer on 11 June. However inadequate the closure process itself, we accepted that the decision was driven by the need to save £60,000 from the council’s 2019/20 budget in order to balance the books. Subsequent document disclosures suggest the situation was not so straightforward.

On 27 June the council’s Corporate Services Scrutiny Committee reviewed spending across the council for 2018/19 and looked ...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2019/07/08/exeter-could-do-better-council-budget-cuts-public-toilet-closures/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Democracy &amp; governance</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Exeter city council</category>
                        
                            <category>Spending cuts</category>
                        
                            <category>Public services</category>
                        
                            <category>Public toilets</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2019/07/08/exeter-could-do-better-council-budget-cuts-public-toilet-closures/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>We already know what to do about the climate crisis. We must get on with doing it as fast as we can.</title>

                    
                        <description>Exeter and Devon council leaders must begin rapid regional decarbonisation now. The quickest, cheapest way to cut emissions in Exeter is to deter combustion engines from entering the city. Clean air legislation offers a basis for action.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>When the Met Office moved to Exeter in 2003, climate change had already emerged as a major existential threat and the IPCC was increasingly sure that human activity was causing it. A 2005 conference hosted here examined the impacts of different levels of climate change and concluded (among other things) that the rate of emissions reduction needed to keep global temperatures to a level that would avoid the most serious consequences would rapidly increase the longer it was delayed.

Following the Exeter co...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2019/06/23/climate-crisis-exeter-devon-carbon-reduction-ultra-low-emission-clean-air-zones-parking-levy-living-streets/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Transport &amp; mobility</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Air quality</category>
                        
                            <category>Climate crisis</category>
                        
                            <category>Congestion</category>
                        
                            <category>Leadership</category>
                        
                            <category>Living streets</category>
                        
                            <category>Exeter city council</category>
                        
                            <category>Exeter city futures</category>
                        
                            <category>Devon county council</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2019/06/23/climate-crisis-exeter-devon-carbon-reduction-ultra-low-emission-clean-air-zones-parking-levy-living-streets/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Caught short - balancing the books in a hurry</title>

                    
                        <description>Exeter City Council has unapologetically confirmed its decision to close 13 public toilets as a money-saving measure with full knowledge of its expected effect on residents and visitors. Can we expect other spending cuts to be handled the same way?</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>Despite government announcements about the end of “austerity”, Exeter City Council has to decide how to reduce its running costs by £2.4 million this year if it is to comply with its legal obligation to produce a balanced budget for 2020/21. The ruling Labour group’s manifesto for the May 2019 local elections gave no indication about how the spending cuts would be made.

There is significant public interest not only in what services will be reduced, but in the process the council will adopt in identifyin...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2019/06/11/exeter-budget-cuts-public-toilet-closures/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Democracy &amp; governance</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Exeter city council</category>
                        
                            <category>Spending cuts</category>
                        
                            <category>Public services</category>
                        
                            <category>Public toilets</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2019/06/11/exeter-budget-cuts-public-toilet-closures/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Preston Street Union rolls out the red carpet</title>

                    
                        <description>The Exeter-based artists explore migration driven by the city's historic wool trade in new work commissioned by RAMM.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>Sir Thomas Dyke Acland stands proud beside the Roman wall in Northernhay Gardens, a century and a half after his death. The inscription on his statue pays tribute to his “generous heart and open hand, which have been ever ready to protect the weak, to relieve the needy, and to succour the oppressed”.

Five figures approach the statue in line, dressed in black utility-style clothing and matching communist caps. They assemble in formation and draw red ping-pong paddles from tool belts, displaying them agai...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2019/06/07/preston-street-union-serge-surge-exeter-city-walls-woollen-trade-ramm-commission/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Arts &amp; culture</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Preston street union</category>
                        
                            <category>Ramm</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2019/06/07/preston-street-union-serge-surge-exeter-city-walls-woollen-trade-ramm-commission/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Exeter Youth Strike 4 Climate - the floodgates are open</title>

                    
                        <description>Exeter is one of the smallest cities in Britain, yet it has produced some of the country's biggest youth strikes. Climate activist Sophie Sleeman recounts the story so far and explains what it means to the young people who are creating a global wave of change.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>Exeter’s youth eco-activist movement burst onto the city’s streets in February 2019 when a thousand children, students and young people gathered at County Hall. We were inspired by sixteen-year-old Greta Thunberg’s protests, which began outside the Swedish parliament the previous summer and had already seen her berate the world’s political leaders for behaving like children at the United Nations climate conference in December.

We occupied a platform beside the council’s offices. Our spontaneous speeches...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2019/06/06/exeter-youth-strike-for-climate-floodgates-open/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Climate &amp; environment</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Climate crisis</category>
                        
                            <category>Youth strike 4 climate</category>
                        
                            <category>Fridays for future</category>
                        
                            <category>Uk student climate network</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2019/06/06/exeter-youth-strike-for-climate-floodgates-open/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Jambassadors feature in pop-up Jazz Toast at Barnfield Theatre</title>

                    
                        <description>Musical director Roz Harding invites us to join an Exeter College Music Academy student collective in a one-night-only experimental exploration of in-the-moment improvisation.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>Jazz is a live music, to be spoken and given away on that day. As Max Roach said, “It comes out of a communal experience. We take our respective instruments and collectively create a thing of beauty.” The Jambassadors, an Exeter College Music Academy student ensemble, channel this spirit to make music together that sounds like them and all the things they are.

On Thursday 6 June at Exeter’s Barnfield Theatre The Jambassadors will be digging deep into improvisation to explore modern jazz-rooted music in ...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2019/05/30/exeter-college-music-academy-jambassadors-jazz-toast-barnfield-theatre/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Arts &amp; culture</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Exeter college</category>
                        
                            <category>Barnfield theatre</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2019/05/30/exeter-college-music-academy-jambassadors-jazz-toast-barnfield-theatre/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Extreme Imagination - Inside the Mind's Eye</title>

                    
                        <description>University of Exeter research fellow Dr Matthew MacKisack guides us through a RAMM exhibition that explores works by artists, writers and makers with widely varying visual imaginations.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>Matthew MacKisack invites you to close your eyes, then to picture the Eiffel Tower. What can you see? Can you pick out the metal struts, follow the line of the tower’s elegant silhouette, grasp the way it stands proud against the Paris skyline? How vivid is the image in your mind’s eye?

An air of quiet concentration falls over the group gathered for a tour of RAMM’s Extreme Imagination exhibition. Standing back, my mind races through myriad images: memories of visits, recollections of photographs and fi...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2019/05/24/extreme-imagination-inside-the-minds-eye-aphantasia-exeter-ramm/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Arts &amp; culture</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Ramm</category>
                        
                            <category>University of exeter</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2019/05/24/extreme-imagination-inside-the-minds-eye-aphantasia-exeter-ramm/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Is EU membership essential to our ability to deal with the climate emergency?</title>

                    
                        <description>Molly Scott Cato, Green Party MEP for the South West, visited Exeter during her re-election campaign to explain why the EU and its Green Group is leading the way on a wide range of progressive policies.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>Most people cannot name one of their their MEPs: how many South West voters know they are represented by six? But many in the region are familiar with the Green Party’s Molly Scott Cato, one of the UK’s 73 MEPs, who is standing here for re-election to the European Parliament on Thursday 23 May.

The Green Party is often characterised by its commitment to tackling climate change. However, as Molly was quick to point out during a recent campaign visit to Exeter, the party has also long promoted a wide rang...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2019/05/21/molly-scott-cato-eu-elections-climate-change-brexit-european-parliament/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Democracy &amp; governance</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>European elections 2019</category>
                        
                            <category>Climate crisis</category>
                        
                            <category>Brexit</category>
                        
                            <category>European parliament</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2019/05/21/molly-scott-cato-eu-elections-climate-change-brexit-european-parliament/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Mount Radford Lawn development proposals conflict with St Leonards community vision</title>

                    
                        <description>Exeter Deaf Academy hopes to sell a school playing field to developers who plan to build luxury homes. Local residents have other ideas about how best to use the land. A dispute is looming over an historic green space driven by prospective profit from planning gain.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>Few passing Mount Radford Lawn, near County Hall on Topsham Road, realise that what looks like an ordinary school playing field has been maintained as recreational green space for at least the past 450 years.

The occupants of an historic house built during the reign of Elizabeth I first looked out over the lawn c.1570. The house was later rebuilt in the Georgian era, when a cedar-lined carriage drive was added along what is now St Leonards Road to lead visitors arriving at the house across the lawn in a...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2019/05/17/mount-radford-lawn-development-proposals-conflict-with-community-vision/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Planning &amp; place</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Mount radford lawn</category>
                        
                            <category>St leonard's</category>
                        
                            <category>Erade</category>
                        
                            <category>Burrington estates</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2019/05/17/mount-radford-lawn-development-proposals-conflict-with-community-vision/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Playing with gender expectations at Barnfield Theatre</title>

                    
                        <description>An Exeter College interpretation of &lt;em&gt;A Midsummer Night's Dream&lt;/em&gt; transforms it into an enchanting contemporary gender-adapted tale.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>On the pink-lit stage of Barnfield Theatre, a teenage boy stands in a dress made of Poundland carrier bags alongside Bottom, Francis Flute and Robin Starveling reimagined as zero-hours workers.

This is just one way in which this Exeter College student production has twisted, shifted and moulded this well-known story for a contemporary audience. While Athens and the forest remain the same, inside are found not only the motley zero-hours crew, but also gender-flipped interpretations of Lysandra, Theseus a...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2019/05/17/exeter-college-midsummer-nights-dream-barnfield-theatre/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Arts &amp; culture</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Exeter college</category>
                        
                            <category>Barnfield theatre</category>
                        
                            <category>Lgbtqia+</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2019/05/17/exeter-college-midsummer-nights-dream-barnfield-theatre/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Rainbow Trail LGBTQIA+ exhibition queers RAMM for Exeter Pride 2019</title>

                    
                        <description>A new collaboration between X-Plore Youth Devon, Exeter College LGBTQ+ society, Natalie McGrath of Dreadnought SW and Dr Jana Funke of the University of Exeter explores gender and sexual diversity across time, place and culture by reimagining objects from the RAMM collections.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>

Exeter RAMM launched an exhibition to celebrate LGBTQIA+ history on the eve of Exeter Pride last night at the second of its after-hours Lates events.

The Rainbow Trail is the result of five months collaborative work between X-Plore Youth Devon, Exeter College LGBTQ+ society, Natalie McGrath of Dreadnought South West and Dr Jana Funke of the University of Exeter.

The trail is the first of its kind for the museum. It invites visitors to consider what it might mean to have the museum as queer space, to ...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2019/05/11/exeter-ramm-rainbow-trail-lgbtqia-exhibition-pride/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Arts &amp; culture</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Ramm</category>
                        
                            <category>Lgbtqia+</category>
                        
                            <category>Exeter pride</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2019/05/11/exeter-ramm-rainbow-trail-lgbtqia-exhibition-pride/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Exeter Labour loses local elections in all three city centre wards</title>

                    
                        <description>Voters in Exeter yesterday elected three new councillors to represent them in the key wards that cover the city centre, with all the city's ruling Exeter Labour group candidates missing out despite the party's confident campaign.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>

Voters in Exeter yesterday elected three new councillors to represent them in the key wards that cover the city centre, with all the city’s ruling Exeter Labour group candidates missing out despite the party’s confident campaign.

There are ongoing controversies around development decisions taken by Exeter’s Labour-run council in these wards that have angered residents. These include the closure of Clifton Hill sports centre and the planned sale of the green space in which it sits to private developers...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2019/05/03/exeter-labour-loses-city-centre-wards-local-elections/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Democracy &amp; governance</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Exeter city council</category>
                        
                            <category>Local elections</category>
                        
                            <category>St davids</category>
                        
                            <category>Newtown &amp; st leonards</category>
                        
                            <category>Duryard &amp; st james</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2019/05/03/exeter-labour-loses-city-centre-wards-local-elections/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Local resident stands as independent candidate in Exeter elections</title>

                    
                        <description>Jemima Moore is a 36 year-old part-time primary school teacher and mother of two young children with little political experience. So why has she decided to stand for election to Exeter City Council on 2 May?</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>Clifton Hill sports centre, in Exeter’s Newtown &amp; St Leonard’s ward, was closed in March 2018 after heavy snowfall caused a major leak in the roof. Local residents heard rumours that it might not re-open and began campaigning to save the place from closure. Then, when Exeter City Council suddenly decided to demolish the building and sell the whole site, they determined to save the nine acre green space in which it sits too.

Despite presenting several popular petitions, demonstrating at the council’s...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2019/04/26/exeter-local-resident-stands-independent-candidate-exeter-elections/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Democracy &amp; governance</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Exeter city council</category>
                        
                            <category>Local elections</category>
                        
                            <category>Newtown &amp; st leonards</category>
                        
                            <category>Clifton hill sport centre</category>
                        
                            <category>Bull meadow park</category>
                        
                            <category>Mount radford lawn</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2019/04/26/exeter-local-resident-stands-independent-candidate-exeter-elections/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Clifton Hill sports centre – the background</title>

                    
                        <description>Storm Emma met the Beast from the East and dumped a huge amount of snow on the roof of Exeter's Clifton Hill sports centre, setting off a chain reaction which has ignited two campaigns and put Exeter City Council's approaches to competence and openness into sharp focus.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>In early March 2018 Storm Emma met the Beast from the East and dumped a huge amount of snow on the roof of Exeter’s Clifton Hill Sports Centre, located in the city’s Newtown &amp; St Leonard’s ward.

This extreme weather event set off a chain reaction which has ignited two campaigns and put Exeter City Council’s approaches to competence and openness into sharp focus.

It also led to an independent candidate from the Save our Green Space campaign standing for Newtown &amp; St Leonard’s in the city council...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2019/04/26/exeter-clifton-hill-sports-centre-background/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Planning &amp; place</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Newtown &amp; st leonards</category>
                        
                            <category>Clifton hill sports centre</category>
                        
                            <category>Exeter city council</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2019/04/26/exeter-clifton-hill-sports-centre-background/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>What does your council know that you don't know you don't know?</title>

                    
                        <description>Extracting information from councils is hard work but increasingly necessary for local democracy.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>As George W. Bush’s Secretary for Defense Donald Rumsfeld once remarked: “There are things we know that we know. There are known unknowns. That is to say there are things that we now know we don’t know. But there are also unknown unknowns. There are things we do not know we don’t know.”

Getting Rumsfeld’s statement word perfect is challenging, but it nevertheless readily comes to mind when observing and monitoring English local authorities. As long ago as 1960 Parliament passed the Public Bodies (Admiss...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2019/04/19/exeter-city-council-information-transparency-democracy/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Democracy &amp; governance</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Democratic deficit</category>
                        
                            <category>Freedom of information</category>
                        
                            <category>Council secrecy</category>
                        
                            <category>Trust &amp; transparency</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2019/04/19/exeter-city-council-information-transparency-democracy/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Is the Greater Exeter Strategic Plan GESPing for air?</title>

                    
                        <description>The Greater Exeter Strategic Plan has been a long time in gestation. When it finally arrives, will it deliver?</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>In summer 2016, four district councils authorised work to start on producing a new statutory planning document, the Greater Exeter Strategic Plan (GESP). This aims to set out the overall spatial strategy and levels of housing and employment land required up to 2040 for the East Devon, Exeter, Mid Devon and Teignbridge council areas (excluding Dartmoor National Park). Devon County Council is also a partner, primarily because of its role as the transport, highways, and minerals and waste planning authority...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2019/04/05/greater-exeter-strategic-plan-update-delivery/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Planning &amp; place</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Greater exeter strategic plan</category>
                        
                            <category>Housing supply</category>
                        
                            <category>Public consultation</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2019/04/05/greater-exeter-strategic-plan-update-delivery/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Exeter Extinction Rebellion stages climate emergency protest</title>

                    
                        <description>Today around 70 people joined the Exeter branch of Extinction Rebellion on the city's streets to demand urgent action to minimise the risk of catastrophic impacts from climate change.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>Today around 70 people joined the Exeter branch of Extinction Rebellion on the city’s streets to demand urgent action to minimise the risk of catastrophic impacts from climate change.

They set up stall on the High Street then set off in a colourful procession around the city centre, waving flags, singing and ringing “the alarm bell of the century”. Group members made speeches, handed out flyers and explained their aims to onlookers. Posters promoting their cause decorated bus shelters, statues and stree...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2019/03/30/extinction-rebellion-climate-emergency-protest-exeter-guildhall-shopping-centre/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Climate &amp; environment</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Extinction rebellion</category>
                        
                            <category>Climate crisis</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2019/03/30/extinction-rebellion-climate-emergency-protest-exeter-guildhall-shopping-centre/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Out of sight, out of mind</title>

                    
                        <description>A performance of &lt;em&gt;From The Light of The Fire, Our Dancing Shadows&lt;/em&gt; in Exeter for Kaleider Mikrofest appears to favour illusion over truth in a confused rendering of Plato's cave allegory that leaves both performers and audience in the dark.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>On a chilly March evening, a small audience assembles in Princesshay. All eyes are on a large, open-sided, circular set. Lengths of electrical cable run between tall shards of lighting truss which support spotlights aimed at the circle’s centre.

The set resembles a sort of pop-concert panopticon. Red velvet rope loops laid out on the ground inscribe seven smaller circles in a flowing, flower shape. At the centre sit several more spotlights, shining outwards. Ushers encourage passersby and stragglers to ...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2019/03/16/kaleider-mikrofest-our-dancing-shadows-exeter-princesshay/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Arts &amp; culture</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Kaleider</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2019/03/16/kaleider-mikrofest-our-dancing-shadows-exeter-princesshay/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Exeter St James regeneration</title>

                    
                        <description>How can the supply of low-cost, incrementally investable city centre accommodation be stimulated to attract and retain creative, technically-skilled young entrepreneurial talent?</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>City knowledge economy development critically depends on the presence of creative, technically-skilled young entrepreneurial talent which, whether locally-grown or graduating, is currently more likely to leave Exeter than stay. Increasing the supply of low-cost, centrally-located accommodation would help improve retention rates while also attracting dynamic incomers who currently head elsewhere to start companies, join growth enterprises and stimulate cultural and night-time economies.

Exeter St James c...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2019/03/08/exeter-st-james-regeneration/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Planning &amp; place</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>St james</category>
                        
                            <category>Knowledge economy</category>
                        
                            <category>Affordable housing</category>
                        
                            <category>University of exeter</category>
                        
                            <category>Congestion</category>
                        
                            <category>Mobility</category>
                        
                            <category>Public realm</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2019/03/08/exeter-st-james-regeneration/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Streets are for people, not cars</title>

                    
                        <description>Cars adversely affect economic output, air quality and wellbeing, take up valuable space when parked and discourage people from walking and cycling when driven. Reducing their use would enhance Exeter's retail and leisure offer, improve public health and attract needed workers to the city.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>Designing towns and cities around private car use was a major error in post-war urban development. What once enabled personal mobility now traps many in traffic going nowhere fast for significant amounts of time. Economic output, air quality, health and wellbeing all suffer, while many streets are filled with vehicles that either take up valuable space when parked or discourage people from walking and cycling when driven. Exeter’s large and expanding Travel to Work Area, rapid suburban and satellite hous...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>http://localhost:3000/2019/03/01/streets-are-for-people-not-cars/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Transport &amp; mobility</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Air quality</category>
                        
                            <category>Cars</category>
                        
                            <category>Congestion</category>
                        
                            <category>Living streets</category>
                        
                            <category>Public health</category>
                        
                            <category>Public realm</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/2019/03/01/streets-are-for-people-not-cars/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

    </channel>
</rss>
