<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Exeter Observer - Independent public interest community journalism</title>

        <description>Exeter Observer publishes news, analysis and investigative feature stories that strengthen civil society and help people participate more effectively in local democracy</description>

        <link>https://exeterobserver.org</link>

        <generator>Jekyll v4.2.0</generator>

        <atom:link href="https://exeterobserver.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>

        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 12:25:52 +0000</pubDate>

        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 12:25:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>

        

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Council pushes back on Liveable Exeter Place Board scrutiny following membership change</title>

                    
                        <description>Exeter City Council has responded to an enquiry about disproportionate Church of England representation on the Liveable Exeter Place Board by accusing Exeter Observer of promoting a &amp;quot;partisan narrative&amp;quot; and claiming our public interest reporting &amp;quot;bears no resemblance to fact&amp;quot;.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>Exeter City Council established the Liveable Exeter Place Board in 2019 to support the delivery of its “ambitious and visionary” Liveable Exeter programme. At the core of this programme is the aspiration to build 12,000 new homes in such a way that a series of communities are created which include retail and employment options and so reduce the need to travel across the city. It is intended to support the council’s goal of reducing the city’s carbon footprint to net zero by 2030.

Exeter Observer’s July ...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>https://exeterobserver.org/2021/02/23/council-refuses-to-provide-information-to-exeter-observer-because-of-a-partisan-narrative/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Democracy &amp; governance</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Liveable exeter place board</category>
                        
                            <category>Exeter city council</category>
                        
                            <category>Property development</category>
                        
                            <category>Planning</category>
                        
                            <category>Placemaking</category>
                        
                            <category>Accountability</category>
                        
                            <category>Transparency</category>
                        
                            <category>Net zero exeter</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://exeterobserver.org/2021/02/23/council-refuses-to-provide-information-to-exeter-observer-because-of-a-partisan-narrative/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Report places Devon County Council among UK's top local authority fossil fuel investors</title>

                    
                        <description>£157 million of Devon Local Government Pension Scheme is invested in companies including Royal Dutch Shell, BP, BHP, Anglo American and ExxonMobil despite local authority climate emergency declarations and carbon reduction commitments.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>

Devon County Council is among the UK’ top local authority fossil fuel investors despite the council declaring a climate emergency nearly two years ago and committing to becoming carbon neutral by 2050.

A report examining local authority staff pension fund investments has found that the Devon Local Government Pension Scheme, which is managed by Devon County Council, invests £157 million of its £4 billion fund in fossil fuel companies such as Royal Dutch Shell, BP, BHP, Anglo American and ExxonMobil.

T...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>https://exeterobserver.org/2021/02/23/devon-county-council-pension-fund-fossil-fuel-investment/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Climate &amp; environment</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Devon county council</category>
                        
                            <category>Exeter city council</category>
                        
                            <category>Pension fund</category>
                        
                            <category>Fossil fuel divestment</category>
                        
                            <category>Devon carbon plan</category>
                        
                            <category>Exeter net zero</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://exeterobserver.org/2021/02/23/devon-county-council-pension-fund-fossil-fuel-investment/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>May local elections to go ahead despite COVID-19 challenges</title>

                    
                        <description>Ban on doorstep canvassing and door to door leaflet distribution likely to favour the two major parties on 6 May as postal and proxy voting encouraged in Exeter City Council, Devon County Council and Devon &amp; Cornwall Police and Crime Commissioner elections.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>

The government has confirmed that local elections will go ahead as planned despite doubts over whether it would be possible to hold the ballots during the coronavirus pandemic. Exeter electors will be asked to vote for city and county councillors and the Devon &amp; Cornwall Police and Crime Commissioner on 6 May.

Exeter usually elects three city councillors to serve four year terms in each of thirteen wards, a total of 39 councillors. A third of the seats, one in each ward, is normally contested in e...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>https://exeterobserver.org/2021/02/20/may-local-elections-go-ahead-despite-covid-19-challenges-doorstep-canvassing-leaflet-distribution-ban/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Democracy &amp; governance</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Local elections</category>
                        
                            <category>Exeter city council</category>
                        
                            <category>Devon county council</category>
                        
                            <category>Police &amp; crime commissioner</category>
                        
                            <category>Coronavirus pandemic</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://exeterobserver.org/2021/02/20/may-local-elections-go-ahead-despite-covid-19-challenges-doorstep-canvassing-leaflet-distribution-ban/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Exeter Science Park STEMM &amp;quot;grow-out building&amp;quot; construction begins</title>

                    
                        <description>A new specialist centre for fast-growth Science, Technology, Engineering, Maths &amp; Medicine businesses will be completed by November 2021.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>

A new building for small and medium-sized enterprises in the science, technology, engineering, maths and medical sectors is being developed at Exeter Science Park on the outskirts of the city.

The 1275 square metre three storey building is being constructed to BREEAM Excellent standards and will provide a combination of office, production, lab and meeting space in eleven units ranging from 65 to 335 square metres.

It is intended to cater for developing businesses which are out-growing accommodation i...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>https://exeterobserver.org/2021/02/17/exeter-science-park-stemm-grow-out-building-construction-begins/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Economy &amp; enterprise</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Exeter science park</category>
                        
                            <category>Stemm</category>
                        
                            <category>Hotsw lep</category>
                        
                            <category>Getting building fund</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://exeterobserver.org/2021/02/17/exeter-science-park-stemm-grow-out-building-construction-begins/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>District heating network planned for new South West Exeter development</title>

                    
                        <description>Local councils are investing up to £7.3 million in a £23 million project to supply a development of 2500 homes with heat from Marsh Barton waste incinerator.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>

Exeter City Council, Teignbridge District Council and Devon County Council have agreed to help fund a project to supply the new South West Exeter development with heat generated by the Marsh Barton waste incinerator.

The scheme is not currently commercially viable because of the need for substantial upfront capital investment and uncertain rates of return, so the councils have agreed to support it with a £7.3 million package of grant and loan funding. The funding is expected to come from developer con...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>https://exeterobserver.org/2021/02/12/south-west-exeter-district-heating-network-housing-infrastructure-fund/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Climate &amp; environment</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Exeter city council</category>
                        
                            <category>Teignbridge district council</category>
                        
                            <category>Devon county council</category>
                        
                            <category>South west exeter</category>
                        
                            <category>Marsh barton</category>
                        
                            <category>Net zero exeter</category>
                        
                            <category>Devon carbon plan</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://exeterobserver.org/2021/02/12/south-west-exeter-district-heating-network-housing-infrastructure-fund/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>University research consortium launches &amp;quot;Accelerate to Net Zero&amp;quot; project</title>

                    
                        <description>The GW4 Alliance of Bath, Bristol, Cardiff and Exeter universities has launched a collaborative project aimed at accelerating decarbonisation across South West England and Wales.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>

The GW4 Alliance, a research consortium of Bath, Bristol, Cardiff and Exeter universities, has launched a collaborative project aimed at accelerating decarbonisation across South West England and Wales.

“Accelerate to Net Zero” aims to turn the region into a “whole-system net zero testbed” where solutions to the challenges of climate change mitigation can be modelled, trialled and developed.

The project will start with a series of workshops focussed on the social and economic implications of net zero...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>https://exeterobserver.org/2021/02/11/gw4-university-research-consortium-launches-accelearate-to-net-zero-climate-change-mitigation-project/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Climate &amp; environment</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Gw4 alliance</category>
                        
                            <category>University of exeter</category>
                        
                            <category>Net zero exeter</category>
                        
                            <category>Devon carbon plan</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://exeterobserver.org/2021/02/11/gw4-university-research-consortium-launches-accelearate-to-net-zero-climate-change-mitigation-project/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>First Liveable Exeter homes are substandard &amp;quot;warehousing for people&amp;quot; which is student accommodation &amp;quot;in all but name&amp;quot;</title>

                    
                        <description>Harlequins shopping centre redevelopment approved by Exeter City Council includes 251 co-living units in seven storey tower block despite widespread opposition from conservation charities and community campaigners who have since appealed to the Secretary of State to call in the decision.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>Exeter City Council’s “Liveable Exeter” vision identifies the redevelopment of the North Gate area of the city centre as one of eight strategic projects intended to “meet people’s needs for homes, jobs and services in the 21st century”. The “transformational housing delivery programme”, which is focused on “priority sites in public ownership”, aims to deliver 308 new homes on the sites of the Harlequins and Guildhall shopping centres.

Curlew Alternatives, a developer which has previously specialised in ...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>https://exeterobserver.org/2020/12/03/harlequins-shopping-centre-redevelopment-substandard-coliving-hotel-student-accommodation-liveable-exeter-city-council-conservation-charities-community-campaign-harm-historic-heritage-assets/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Planning &amp; place</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Exeter city council</category>
                        
                            <category>Harlequins</category>
                        
                            <category>Co-living</category>
                        
                            <category>Liveable exeter</category>
                        
                            <category>Purpose built student accommodation</category>
                        
                            <category>Affordable housing</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://exeterobserver.org/2020/12/03/harlequins-shopping-centre-redevelopment-substandard-coliving-hotel-student-accommodation-liveable-exeter-city-council-conservation-charities-community-campaign-harm-historic-heritage-assets/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Hospital creates parking for 200 cars despite city climate crisis goals</title>

                    
                        <description>Royal Devon &amp; Exeter Hospital says new parking &amp;quot;temporary&amp;quot; but no end-date given in planning application and no hard evidence of need provided.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>The Royal Devon &amp; Exeter NHS Foundation Trust is pushing ahead with plans to provide 205 new car parking spaces on trust-owned land near the main hospital site at Wonford.

It is carrying out the development without obtaining permission from the local planning authority under powers introduced in April as part of the government’s emergency measures to combat the coronavirus.



The new legislation gives health and local authorities conditional but wide-ranging powers to carry out development “for the...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>https://exeterobserver.org/2020/10/28/royal-devon-and-exeter-hospital-wonford-nhs-trust-creates-200-car-parking-spaces-despite-city-climate-crisis-goals-local-plan-policy-exeter-net-zero-air-quality/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Climate &amp; environment</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Royal devon &amp; exeter hospital</category>
                        
                            <category>Exeter city council</category>
                        
                            <category>Exeter city futures</category>
                        
                            <category>Net zero exeter</category>
                        
                            <category>Liveable exeter place board</category>
                        
                            <category>Car parking</category>
                        
                            <category>Climate crisis</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://exeterobserver.org/2020/10/28/royal-devon-and-exeter-hospital-wonford-nhs-trust-creates-200-car-parking-spaces-despite-city-climate-crisis-goals-local-plan-policy-exeter-net-zero-air-quality/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Exeter City Council executive members take direct control of city planning decisions</title>

                    
                        <description>Council's executive now possesses majority on city planning committee, with council leader and planning portfolio holder also included despite national guidance, offering basis to challenge decisions and increasing democratic deficit.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>The number of executive members on Exeter City Council’s planning committee has more than doubled since April 2016 to give the executive a built-in near two-thirds majority on planning policy and development decisions affecting the city.

No other planning authority in the south west peninsula follows this practice, where the highest proportion of executive members on other planning committees is only one third, and six local authorities have no executive members on their planning committees at all.

The...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>https://exeterobserver.org/2020/09/07/exeter-city-council-executive-planning-committee-membership-majority-despite-local-government-association-guidance/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Democracy &amp; governance</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Exeter city council</category>
                        
                            <category>Planning policy</category>
                        
                            <category>Development control</category>
                        
                            <category>Transparency</category>
                        
                            <category>Accountability</category>
                        
                            <category>Liveable exeter place board</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://exeterobserver.org/2020/09/07/exeter-city-council-executive-planning-committee-membership-majority-despite-local-government-association-guidance/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Council abandons temporary COVID-19 cycling and walking safety plans in Exeter city centre</title>

                    
                        <description>Devon County Council cites &amp;quot;pushback&amp;quot; from traders as schemes on North Street, South Street, Fore Street and Cowick Street are scrapped. Meanwhile temporary changes in Topsham are dropped after &amp;quot;snap poll&amp;quot;.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>Devon County Council has abandoned its plans for temporary COVID-19 cycling and walking safety measures in Exeter city centre despite widespread support for the changes from survey respondents and consultees.

The proposed changes were to be funded under the first phase of a £250 million coronavirus emergency active travel fund announced by the Secretary of State for Transport on 9 May.

The county council has repeatedly said it would provide “improved foot and cycle access to the city centre via South S...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>https://exeterobserver.org/2020/08/04/devon-county-council-covid-19-temporary-cycling-and-walking-infrastructure-safety-plans-exeter-city-centre/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Transport &amp; mobility</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Devon county council</category>
                        
                            <category>Coronavirus</category>
                        
                            <category>Cycling &amp; walking</category>
                        
                            <category>Exeter city centre</category>
                        
                            <category>Topsham</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://exeterobserver.org/2020/08/04/devon-county-council-covid-19-temporary-cycling-and-walking-infrastructure-safety-plans-exeter-city-centre/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

    </channel>
</rss>
