<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Exeter Observer - Independent public interest community journalism</title>

        <description>Exeter Observer publishes news, analysis and investigative feature stories that strengthen civil society and help people participate more effectively in local democracy</description>

        <link>https://exeterobserver.org</link>

        <generator>Jekyll v4.2.0</generator>

        <atom:link href="https://exeterobserver.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>

        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 11:58:59 +0000</pubDate>

        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 11:58:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>

        

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>First Liveable Exeter homes are substandard &amp;quot;warehousing for people&amp;quot; which is student accommodation &amp;quot;in all but name&amp;quot;</title>

                    
                        <description>Harlequins shopping centre redevelopment approved by Exeter City Council includes 251 co-living units in seven storey tower block despite widespread opposition from conservation charities and community campaigners who have since appealed to the Secretary of State to call in the decision.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>Exeter City Council’s “Liveable Exeter” vision identifies the redevelopment of the North Gate area of the city centre as one of eight strategic projects intended to “meet people’s needs for homes, jobs and services in the 21st century”. The “transformational housing delivery programme”, which is focused on “priority sites in public ownership”, aims to deliver 308 new homes on the sites of the Harlequins and Guildhall shopping centres.

Curlew Alternatives, a developer which has previously specialised in ...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>https://exeterobserver.org/2020/12/03/harlequins-shopping-centre-redevelopment-substandard-coliving-hotel-student-accommodation-liveable-exeter-city-council-conservation-charities-community-campaign-harm-historic-heritage-assets/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Planning &amp; place</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Exeter city council</category>
                        
                            <category>Harlequins</category>
                        
                            <category>Co-living</category>
                        
                            <category>Liveable exeter</category>
                        
                            <category>Purpose built student accommodation</category>
                        
                            <category>Affordable housing</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://exeterobserver.org/2020/12/03/harlequins-shopping-centre-redevelopment-substandard-coliving-hotel-student-accommodation-liveable-exeter-city-council-conservation-charities-community-campaign-harm-historic-heritage-assets/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Hospital creates parking for 200 cars despite city climate crisis goals</title>

                    
                        <description>Royal Devon &amp; Exeter Hospital says new parking &amp;quot;temporary&amp;quot; but no end-date given in planning application and no hard evidence of need provided.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>The Royal Devon &amp; Exeter NHS Foundation Trust is pushing ahead with plans to provide 205 new car parking spaces on trust-owned land near the main hospital site at Wonford.

It is carrying out the development without obtaining permission from the local planning authority under powers introduced in April as part of the government’s emergency measures to combat the coronavirus.



The new legislation gives health and local authorities conditional but wide-ranging powers to carry out development “for the...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>https://exeterobserver.org/2020/10/28/royal-devon-and-exeter-hospital-wonford-nhs-trust-creates-200-car-parking-spaces-despite-city-climate-crisis-goals-local-plan-policy-exeter-net-zero-air-quality/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Climate &amp; environment</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Royal devon &amp; exeter hospital</category>
                        
                            <category>Exeter city council</category>
                        
                            <category>Exeter city futures</category>
                        
                            <category>Net zero exeter</category>
                        
                            <category>Liveable exeter place board</category>
                        
                            <category>Car parking</category>
                        
                            <category>Climate crisis</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://exeterobserver.org/2020/10/28/royal-devon-and-exeter-hospital-wonford-nhs-trust-creates-200-car-parking-spaces-despite-city-climate-crisis-goals-local-plan-policy-exeter-net-zero-air-quality/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Exeter City Council executive members take direct control of city planning decisions</title>

                    
                        <description>Council's executive now possesses majority on city planning committee, with council leader and planning portfolio holder also included despite national guidance, offering basis to challenge decisions and increasing democratic deficit.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>The number of executive members on Exeter City Council’s planning committee has more than doubled since April 2016 to give the executive a built-in near two-thirds majority on planning policy and development decisions affecting the city.

No other planning authority in the south west peninsula follows this practice, where the highest proportion of executive members on other planning committees is only one third, and six local authorities have no executive members on their planning committees at all.

The...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>https://exeterobserver.org/2020/09/07/exeter-city-council-executive-planning-committee-membership-majority-despite-local-government-association-guidance/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Democracy &amp; governance</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Exeter city council</category>
                        
                            <category>Planning policy</category>
                        
                            <category>Development control</category>
                        
                            <category>Transparency</category>
                        
                            <category>Accountability</category>
                        
                            <category>Liveable exeter place board</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://exeterobserver.org/2020/09/07/exeter-city-council-executive-planning-committee-membership-majority-despite-local-government-association-guidance/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Council abandons temporary COVID-19 cycling and walking safety plans in Exeter city centre</title>

                    
                        <description>Devon County Council cites &amp;quot;pushback&amp;quot; from traders as schemes on North Street, South Street, Fore Street and Cowick Street are scrapped. Meanwhile temporary changes in Topsham are dropped after &amp;quot;snap poll&amp;quot;.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>Devon County Council has abandoned its plans for temporary COVID-19 cycling and walking safety measures in Exeter city centre despite widespread support for the changes from survey respondents and consultees.

The proposed changes were to be funded under the first phase of a £250 million coronavirus emergency active travel fund announced by the Secretary of State for Transport on 9 May.

The county council has repeatedly said it would provide “improved foot and cycle access to the city centre via South S...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>https://exeterobserver.org/2020/08/04/devon-county-council-covid-19-temporary-cycling-and-walking-infrastructure-safety-plans-exeter-city-centre/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Transport &amp; mobility</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Devon county council</category>
                        
                            <category>Coronavirus</category>
                        
                            <category>Cycling &amp; walking</category>
                        
                            <category>Exeter city centre</category>
                        
                            <category>Topsham</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://exeterobserver.org/2020/08/04/devon-county-council-covid-19-temporary-cycling-and-walking-infrastructure-safety-plans-exeter-city-centre/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Is the &amp;quot;Net Zero&amp;quot; Exeter plan fit for purpose? Part I&amp;colon; Exeter&amp;apos;s carbon footprint</title>

                    
                        <description>Exeter City Futures&amp;apos; carbon reduction plan ignores over a million tonnes of carbon emissions and massively underestimates the challenges facing the city. First in a series examining its flaws by Fridays For Future youth climate activists.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>The Committee on Climate Change published its annual report on 25 June, two days before the anniversary of the UK’s carbon reduction pledge being signed into law. The report rebuked the government’s slow progress, urging much more dramatic action to avoid a post-pandemic emissions rebound.

The government nevertheless announced spending plans a few days later that dismayed environmental experts after spending billions of pounds during lockdown bailing out airlines, carmakers and oil companies without att...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>https://exeterobserver.org/2020/07/21/net-zero-exeter-2030-plan-part-one-exeters-carbon-footprint-exeter-city-futures-exeter-city-council-fridays-for-future-climate-activists/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Climate &amp; environment</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Net zero exeter</category>
                        
                            <category>Exeter city futures</category>
                        
                            <category>Exeter city council</category>
                        
                            <category>Climate crisis</category>
                        
                            <category>Fridays for future</category>
                        
                            <category>Carbon footprint</category>
                        
                            <category>Exeter airport</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://exeterobserver.org/2020/07/21/net-zero-exeter-2030-plan-part-one-exeters-carbon-footprint-exeter-city-futures-exeter-city-council-fridays-for-future-climate-activists/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Unelected Liveable Exeter Place Board created to oversee city from the shadows</title>

                    
                        <description>Exeter City Council has convened an unelected board that meets in private, does not publish its discussions or decisions and is taking responsibility for major policies which will determine Exeter's future.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>An assembly of the great and the good described by Exeter City Council’s chief executive, Karime Hassan, as “conscientious, talented people from all backgrounds who want to work in the best interests of the city” has been meeting in private in recent months.

Its membership is unelected, it does not publish its discussions or decisions and it is taking responsibility for major policies which will determine Exeter’s future.

The city council has had a predilection for such bodies for some time: recent arr...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>https://exeterobserver.org/2020/07/14/unelected-liveable-exeter-place-board-created-by-city-council-to-take-responsibility-for-major-policies-determining-Exeter-future-development/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Democracy &amp; governance</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Liveable exeter place board</category>
                        
                            <category>Exeter city council</category>
                        
                            <category>Property development</category>
                        
                            <category>Spatial development</category>
                        
                            <category>Accountability</category>
                        
                            <category>Transparency</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://exeterobserver.org/2020/07/14/unelected-liveable-exeter-place-board-created-by-city-council-to-take-responsibility-for-major-policies-determining-Exeter-future-development/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Exeter rough sleepers in COVID-19 emergency accommodation face uncertain future</title>

                    
                        <description>Exeter City Council has yet to confirm whether it will use any of the £2.15m Rough Sleeping Initiative funding it has received since 2018 to keep housing rough sleepers when government emergency accommodation funding runs out.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>When the coronavirus pandemic broke out, the government announced £3.2 million in emergency funding for local authorities to move all rough sleepers and other vulnerable homeless people into temporary accommodation. Each local authority allocation was based on the number of rough sleepers it reported in the autumn 2019 snapshot count.

Exeter’s performance in the count was poor: it reported the 25th highest number of rough sleepers among 316 local authorities in England, with a higher rate of rough sleep...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>https://exeterobserver.org/2020/06/10/exeter-rough-sleepers-covid19-emergency-accommodation-rough-sleeping-initiative-homelessness/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Community &amp; society</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Exeter city council</category>
                        
                            <category>Rough sleeping initiative</category>
                        
                            <category>Coronavirus</category>
                        
                            <category>Covid-19 emergency accommodation</category>
                        
                            <category>Night shelter</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://exeterobserver.org/2020/06/10/exeter-rough-sleepers-covid19-emergency-accommodation-rough-sleeping-initiative-homelessness/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Exeter City Council accepts climate emergency plan to make city carbon neutral by 2030</title>

                    
                        <description>Chief Executive warns that resourcing the plan is &amp;quot;problematic&amp;quot; given COVID-19 financial challenges and that lack of resources limits the council's capacity for immediate practical action.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>Exeter City Council has accepted a plan intended to make the city carbon neutral by 2030. At a meeting on Tuesday its Executive agreed to recommend that the Net Zero Exeter plan published by Exeter City Futures in April should be adopted by the council as a policy “to inform all policy documents, plans and corporate decision making in response to the climate emergency”.

The plan sets out a range of actions that Exeter City Futures believes can deliver the city council’s target of a carbon neutral Exeter...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>https://exeterobserver.org/2020/06/05/exeter-city-futures-net-zero-exeter-2030-plan-exeter-city-council-executive-decision/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Climate &amp; environment</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Exeter city council</category>
                        
                            <category>Climate crisis</category>
                        
                            <category>Net zero exeter</category>
                        
                            <category>Coronavirus</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://exeterobserver.org/2020/06/05/exeter-city-futures-net-zero-exeter-2030-plan-exeter-city-council-executive-decision/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Devon County Council fails to deliver promised COVID-19 cycling and walking infrastructure</title>

                    
                        <description>Deadline for action on social distancing for safe travel set by county cabinet member passes despite Devon receiving £1.7 million share of government emergency fund.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>Devon County Council has delivered none of the pop-up infrastructure it proposed to enable safe cycling and walking in Exeter during the coronavirus pandemic.

Andrew Leadbetter, county councillor for Wearside &amp; Topsham and Exeter’s only county cabinet member, confirmed that proposals outlined by the county nearly three weeks ago would be delivered by today.

However no changes have been made to the road layout on Fore Street, South Street, North Street, Cowick Street or Magdalen Road.

Andrew Leadbe...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>https://exeterobserver.org/2020/06/01/devon-county-council-cycling-walking-infrastructure-delivery-failure-department-for-transport-new-road-layouts-funding/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Transport &amp; mobility</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Devon county council</category>
                        
                            <category>Coronavirus</category>
                        
                            <category>Cycling &amp; walking</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://exeterobserver.org/2020/06/01/devon-county-council-cycling-walking-infrastructure-delivery-failure-department-for-transport-new-road-layouts-funding/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Coronavirus exposes council failure to deliver Exeter transport plans</title>

                    
                        <description>Devon County Council's failure to deliver overdue Exeter transport strategy and cycling and walking plan has led to an inadequate response to government demands for emergency coronavirus road layout changes.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>

Two weeks have passed since the government announced a £250 million emergency active travel fund in response to dramatic increases in walking and cycling during coronavirus lockdown.

The fund is intended to relieve pressure on public transport as lockdown eases by enabling local authorities to create pop-up bike lanes with protected space for cycling, wider pavements for pedestrians and car-free corridors to ensure higher levels of active travel can continue.

Public transport will only be able to car...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>https://exeterobserver.org/2020/05/22/devon-county-council-local-cycling-walking-infrastructure-plans-exeter-transport-strategy-department-for-transport-new-road-layout-for-coronavirus-social-distancing/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Transport &amp; mobility</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Devon county council</category>
                        
                            <category>Exeter transport strategy</category>
                        
                            <category>Local cycling &amp; walking infrastructure plan</category>
                        
                            <category>Covid-19</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://exeterobserver.org/2020/05/22/devon-county-council-local-cycling-walking-infrastructure-plans-exeter-transport-strategy-department-for-transport-new-road-layout-for-coronavirus-social-distancing/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

    </channel>
</rss>
