<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Exeter Observer - Independent public interest community journalism</title>

        <description>Exeter Observer publishes news, analysis and investigative features and aims to strengthen civil society and help people participate more effectively in local democracy</description>

        <link>https://exeterobserver.org</link>

        <!--<generator>Jekyll v4.2.0</generator>-->

        <atom:link href="https://exeterobserver.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>

        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 08:09:21 +0100</pubDate>

        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 08:09:21 +0100</lastBuildDate>

        

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Council announces plan to produce &amp;quot;Exeter the Musical&amp;quot; at city's Corn Exchange</title>

                    
                        <description>Exeter City Council has announced a plan to produce a musical theatre extravaganza billed as &amp;quot;an ambitious celebration of a better life in the world's most world-class city&amp;quot; as part of its UNESCO City of Literature celebrations.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>Exeter City Council has announced plans to produce a new musical theatre extravaganza to celebrate the city’s UNESCO City of Literature status.

Exeter the Musical, billed as “an ambitious celebration of a better life in the world’s most world-class city”, will also form the principal plank of the city council’s post-pandemic economic recovery package.

The musical’s narrative will take its inspiration from The Nun’s Priest’s Tale, one of The Canterbury Tales by the fourteenth century poet Geoffrey Chauc...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>https://exeterobserver.org/2021/04/01/exeter-the-musical/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Arts &amp; culture</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Exeter city council</category>
                        
                            <category>Exeter culture</category>
                        
                            <category>Unesco city of literature</category>
                        
                            <category>Visit exeter</category>
                        
                            <category>Liveable exeter</category>
                        
                            <category>Exeter live better</category>
                        
                            <category>Musical theatre</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://exeterobserver.org/2021/04/01/exeter-the-musical/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Selective use of statistics presents an unbalanced account of Exeter's economic &amp; environmental status</title>

                    
                        <description>Exeter City Council's Chief Executive uses statistics to show the city in a good light, but in doing so presents a picture which omits important information about the city's true position.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>Twitter followers of Karime Hassan, Exeter City Council’s Chief Executive and Growth Director, may have noticed his frequent recourse to statistics which paint the city in a favourable light. The most recent such tweet, posted on 17 March, read:

“According to @CentreforCities Exeter is among the top 10 cities in the UK for: population growth (2nd), housing stock growth (6th), air quality (5th), low CO2 emissions (7th), low claimant count (2nd) &amp; low proportion of working age pop’n with no formal qua...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>https://exeterobserver.org/2021/03/26/selective-use-of-statistics-presents-unbalanced-account-of-exeter-economic-and-environmental-status-city-council-chief-executive-centre-for-cities/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Economy &amp; enterprise</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Exeter city council</category>
                        
                            <category>Karime hassan</category>
                        
                            <category>Centre for cities</category>
                        
                            <category>Housing</category>
                        
                            <category>Air quality</category>
                        
                            <category>Carbon emissions</category>
                        
                            <category>Employment</category>
                        
                            <category>Qualifications</category>
                        
                            <category>Earnings</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://exeterobserver.org/2021/03/26/selective-use-of-statistics-presents-unbalanced-account-of-exeter-economic-and-environmental-status-city-council-chief-executive-centre-for-cities/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Developer plans to convert retail units in Exeter city centre block to additional student bedrooms</title>

                    
                        <description>Conversion of five of eleven shop/leisure units at The Depot on Cheeke Street would add nineteen rooms to existing 715 bedrooms in monolithic PBSA.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>The developers of a purpose built student block in Exeter city centre have applied for planning permission to convert several of its street-level retail units to student accommodation.

The Depot currently includes eleven ground floor retail and leisure units in addition to 715 student bedrooms. But the developer has so far failed to secure commercial tenants for eight of the units.

The proposals are to create nineteen student bedrooms by reconfiguring five of these units, which would increase the total...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>https://exeterobserver.org/2021/03/26/developer-plans-to-convert-retail-units-in-exeter-city-centre-block-to-additional-student-bedrooms/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Planning &amp; place</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Purpose built student accommodation</category>
                        
                            <category>Exeter city centre</category>
                        
                            <category>Retail</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://exeterobserver.org/2021/03/26/developer-plans-to-convert-retail-units-in-exeter-city-centre-block-to-additional-student-bedrooms/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Okehampton to Exeter &amp;quot;Dartmoor Line&amp;quot; passenger rail service reinstatement confirmed</title>

                    
                        <description>£40 million Department for Transport &amp;quot;Restoring your Railway&amp;quot; funding to enable trains every two hours by end of this year, with plans to increase to hourly service during 2022. Stakeholders combine to get South West infrastructure needs onto Whitehall agenda.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>The Department for Transport has confirmed that regular passenger rail services will be reinstated on the Okehampton to Exeter line at the end of this year.

The new service will initially run every two hours, and is expected to increase to hourly towards the end of 2022, subject to further upgrades. Eight 130-seat trains will run each day in either direction between 7am and 10pm. Journey time from Okehampton to Exeter will be 40 minutes.

Regular passenger services on the newly-branded Dartmoor Line wer...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>https://exeterobserver.org/2021/03/19/okehamption-to-exeter-dartmoor-line-passenger-rail-service-reinstatement-confirmed-40-million-department-for-transport-restoring-your-railway-fund/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Transport &amp; mobility</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Department for transport</category>
                        
                            <category>Great western railway</category>
                        
                            <category>Network rail</category>
                        
                            <category>Devon &amp; cornwall rail partnership</category>
                        
                            <category>Okerail forum</category>
                        
                            <category>Devon county council</category>
                        
                            <category>Peninsula rail task force</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://exeterobserver.org/2021/03/19/okehamption-to-exeter-dartmoor-line-passenger-rail-service-reinstatement-confirmed-40-million-department-for-transport-restoring-your-railway-fund/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Atmospheric concentration of CO2 now 50% above pre-industrial levels</title>

                    
                        <description>Met Office says 2021 will be first year on record in which symbolic threshold breached for more than a few days as UK prepares to host COP26 United Nations Climate Change Conference.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>

The concentration of carbon dioxide in the atmosphere is passing 417 parts per million, a 50% increase since large scale greenhouse gas emissions caused by humans burning fossil fuels began during the industrial revolution.

Measurements at the Mauna Loa Observatory in Hawaii show that carbon dioxide concentrations were above this level on several days in February and March this year.

The Met Office expects carbon dioxide levels to remain above this symbolic threshold for around three months during 20...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>https://exeterobserver.org/2021/03/18/atmospheric-carbon-dioxide-now-50-per-cent-higher-than-pre-industrial-levels-met-office/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Climate &amp; environment</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Met office</category>
                        
                            <category>University of exeter</category>
                        
                            <category>Climate change</category>
                        
                            <category>Cop26</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://exeterobserver.org/2021/03/18/atmospheric-carbon-dioxide-now-50-per-cent-higher-than-pre-industrial-levels-met-office/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Maclaines Warehouses development tests Exeter Heritage Harbour status</title>

                    
                        <description>Decisions taken behind closed doors in favour of commercial interests threaten maritime and waterway heritage vision for Exeter’s historic quay, canal and canal basin.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>In 1981 Exeter City Council was faced with several decaying and under-used assets around its historic quay and canal basin which required capital investment to create a viable future. Severe central government controls on council spending made it impracticable to fund the work from the council’s own capital programme, so it set up the Exeter Canal and Quay Trust as a development and regeneration vehicle.

This approach allowed spending through the trust to remain off the council’s books. The challenge wa...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>https://exeterobserver.org/2021/03/17/maclaines-warehouses-development-tests-exeter-heritage-harbour-status-ship-canal-basin-quay-topsham-brewery/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Planning &amp; place</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Exeter canal and quay trust</category>
                        
                            <category>Friends of the exeter ship canal</category>
                        
                            <category>Exeter civic society</category>
                        
                            <category>Exeter city council</category>
                        
                            <category>Maclaines warehouses</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://exeterobserver.org/2021/03/17/maclaines-warehouses-development-tests-exeter-heritage-harbour-status-ship-canal-basin-quay-topsham-brewery/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>£37.5 million council maintenance backlog caused by underinvestment to be part-funded by asset sales</title>

                    
                        <description>Exeter City Council has allowed property assets to deteriorate while prioritising new schemes including the £44 million St Sidwell's Point leisure centre, forcing it to identify assets for sale to pay its outstanding repair bills.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>Maintenance – the property upkeep variety, not post-divorce payments – is seldom glamourous or even interesting. It is readily overlooked by politicians and bureaucrats whose careers are advanced by being seen to innovate. A brand new play facility and its attendant publicity gets more brownie points than the unnoticed activity of preventing an old one from falling apart.

Every so often, however, the past hits the present with an unpleasant surprise, commonly in the form of a whopping bill.

Past realit...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>https://exeterobserver.org/2021/03/09/37.5-million-council-maintenance-backlog-underinvestment-asset-sales-44-million-st-sidwells-point-leisure-centre/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Democracy &amp; governance</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Exeter city council</category>
                        
                            <category>Capital programme</category>
                        
                            <category>Assets maintenance</category>
                        
                            <category>Spending priorities</category>
                        
                            <category>St sidwell's point</category>
                        
                            <category>Leisure centre</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://exeterobserver.org/2021/03/09/37.5-million-council-maintenance-backlog-underinvestment-asset-sales-44-million-st-sidwells-point-leisure-centre/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Top floor of former Debenhams store to be converted into cinema</title>

                    
                        <description>Princesshay owner's proposals for change of use to four screen cinema and cafe/bar have been under discussion since November 2019.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>

Princesshay’s owners have applied for planning permission to convert the top floor of the former Debenhams store into a cinema and cafe/bar.

The conversion would involve raising most of the roof line by between 2.5 and 3.5 metres to accommodate the height of four cinema screens, and the conversion of part of the ground floor to provide dedicated access to the complex, which would include a foyer and bar/restaurant.

Tenants are being sought for the rest of the former Debenhams store. The ground, first...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>https://exeterobserver.org/2021/03/04/exeter-princesshay-debenhams-cinema-bar-restaurant-use-change-application/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Arts &amp; culture</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Princesshay</category>
                        
                            <category>Debenhams</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://exeterobserver.org/2021/03/04/exeter-princesshay-debenhams-cinema-bar-restaurant-use-change-application/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Door to door campaigning for May local elections to go ahead after all</title>

                    
                        <description>Government announces relaxation of coronavirus restrictions on election canvassing from next Monday 8 March in step with planned lockdown rule changes.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>

The government has announced that restrictions on door to door campaigning in the run-up to the local elections on 6 May will be relaxed from next week, in step with its planned changes to lockdown rules. The new regulations only apply in England: the devolved administrations are setting out separate plans for Scotland, Wales and Northern Ireland.

From next Monday 8 March, the same day as schools and colleges reopen and outdoor recreation or exercise with one other person becomes allowed, outdoor elec...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>https://exeterobserver.org/2021/03/02/door-to-door-campaigning-for-may-local-elections-to-go-ahead-from-8-march/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Democracy &amp; governance</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Local elections</category>
                        
                            <category>Exeter city council</category>
                        
                            <category>Devon county council</category>
                        
                            <category>Police &amp; crime commissioner</category>
                        
                            <category>Coronavirus pandemic</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://exeterobserver.org/2021/03/02/door-to-door-campaigning-for-may-local-elections-to-go-ahead-from-8-march/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

            

                <item>
                    <title>Council pushes back on Liveable Exeter Place Board scrutiny following membership change</title>

                    
                        <description>Exeter City Council has responded to an enquiry about disproportionate Church of England representation on the Liveable Exeter Place Board by accusing Exeter Observer of promoting a &amp;quot;partisan narrative&amp;quot; and claiming our public interest reporting &amp;quot;bears no resemblance to fact&amp;quot;.</description>
                    

                    
                        <extract>Exeter City Council established the Liveable Exeter Place Board in 2019 to support the delivery of its “ambitious and visionary” Liveable Exeter programme. At the core of this programme is the aspiration to build 12,000 new homes in such a way that a series of communities are created which include retail and employment options and so reduce the need to travel across the city. It is intended to support the council’s goal of reducing the city’s carbon footprint to net zero by 2030.

Exeter Observer’s July ...</extract>
                    

                    
                        <link>https://exeterobserver.org/2021/02/23/exeter-city-council-pushes-back-on-liveable-exeter-place-board-scrutiny-following-membership-change/</link>
                    

                    
                        <category>Democracy &amp; governance</category>
                    

                    
                        
                            <category>Liveable exeter place board</category>
                        
                            <category>Exeter city council</category>
                        
                            <category>Property development</category>
                        
                            <category>Planning</category>
                        
                            <category>Placemaking</category>
                        
                            <category>Accountability</category>
                        
                            <category>Transparency</category>
                        
                            <category>Net zero exeter</category>
                        
                    

                    
                        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                    

                    
                        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://exeterobserver.org/2021/02/23/exeter-city-council-pushes-back-on-liveable-exeter-place-board-scrutiny-following-membership-change/</guid>
                    

                </item>

            

        

    </channel>
</rss>
